I think what we're seeing now, what unfolds in front of our eyes, is a genocidal situation
by which people are targeted, whether they are children, babies, in hospital or in schools.
And this is a massive operation of killing, of ethnic cleansing, of depopulation. The pretext
for that kind of savagery is revenge for what Hamas did on the 7th of October. But I think the real
intention here is not just revenge, but trying to exploit what happened on the 7th of October
to create new realities in historical Palestine. You called it a new Nakba. I think that this is,
the Nakba has never really ended for the Palestinians, so it's a new horrific chapter
in the ongoing Nakba that the Palestinians are suffering here. I think the main attempt here
is to make sure that people do not understand the context in which the Hamas operation occurred,
to totally dis-historicize that event, to forget about the 15 years of inhuman siege on Gaza,
of 56 years of a ruthless occupation and ethnic cleansing in the West Bank and 75 years of not
allowing refugees to come back to their homes. I think this is an attempt to nazify the Palestinians.
The nazification of the Palestinians is meant to, first of all, license Israeli policies without any
consideration to international law or human rights, and secondly, to divert us from talking about the
real issue here, which is not the Hamas or its actions on the 7th of October, but rather the
situation that bred this kind of violence. Rather than talking about the symptoms of violence,
we should talk about the source of violence. And the source of violence has not changed.
We have millions of Palestinians for years being oppressed, ruled and controlled by Israel,
and they are fighting with the means that they have. And this is going to go on, unless, of course,
there is a willingness to go back to the negotiation table.